HAMDI BEN HENDA

Sousse, Tunisia | +330763712010 | benhenda.hamdi@gmail.com | Linkedin.com/in/benhendahamdi | My portfolio

SUMMARY

Software developer with more than 5 years of experience in creating and updating software solutions, during this period I gained experience as a FrontEnd developer working on innovative and challenging projects and getting involved in all phases of the project lifecycle from analysis to deployment.

SKILLS

Javascript | Typescript | HTML | CSS | PHP | MySQL | REST APIS | Angular | Drupal | Symfony | Twig | Prestashop | Linux | GIT | GitFlow | Docker | E-commerce | Scrum | Agile Methodologies

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Since March 2022

External consultant (Angular / Drupal) at Capgemini, Paris, France

- Involved in the full software development lifecycle; analysis, developing, testing and implementing.
- Maintain and develop Frontend features (Angular / Drupal)
- Fixing CSS and SCSS display bugs (Angular / Drupal)
- Collaborate in SCRUM method with a team of 20 developers.

September 2019 to March 2022

Software Developer, GenextIT, Sousse, Tunisia

- Involved in the full software development lifecycle; analysis, developing, testing and implementing.
- Reviewing the work of the development team to improve performance and code quality.
- Contribute to the maintenance and continuous improvement of client projects.
- Serving as a mentor to less experienced software developers and advising them.
- Looking for new ways to improve software quality, and finding solutions to resolve technical problems during project development.

March 2019 to September 2019

Php / Prestashop Developer, <u>Dotit</u>, Sousse, Tunisia

- Contribute to the maintenance and continuous improvement of client projects.
- Front End Developer: Web integration via the appropriate development languages.
- Develop new functionalities in frontend (Angular) and backend (PHP).

August 2017 to February 2019

Php / Prestashop Developer, Webspirit, Sousse, Tunisia

- Contribute to the maintenance and continuous improvement of client projects.
- Front End Developer: Web integration via the appropriate development languages.
- Develop new functionalities in frontend (Angular) and backend (PHP).
- Develop and maintain Prestashop modules

February 2017 to August 2017

FrontEnd Developer, Dev-future, Sousse, Tunisia

- Front End Developer: Web integration via the appropriate development languages.
- Create design and develop showcase website

PROJECTS

ONISR [Capgemini]:

Technologies used: Drupal, Angular, Twig, Html, CSS, Docker, Jenkins

- Maintain and develop Frontend features (Angular / Drupal)
- Contribute to maintaining the RGAA of the ONISR.

<u>Clicknmeal</u> [GenextIT]: a platform for ethical and responsible networking in the catering industry. It allows the customer to reserve a table online or to place a take-out order or have it delivered.

Technologies used: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Angular, Html, CSS

- Lead Developer Front Angular
- Build a web application for multiple user types

Grembat [GenextIT]: is a platform for managing the construction and maintenance of buildings

Technologies used: ReactNative, Redux, Saga

• Lead - Dev Front Angular

<u>Lokatout</u> [GenextIT]: an application aims to fight against overconsumption, unnecessary purchases and pollution. The principle is to offer rental properties whose usefulness is punctual.

Technologies used: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, ReactNative.

• Lead - Dev Front Angular

Geant Drive [Dot-it]:

Technologies used: Prestashop, Twig, Php, HTML/CSS, JS.

• Prestashop & web developer

EDUCATION

2011-2016: Isitcom Hammem-sousse, Tunisia [bachelor's degree in multimedia and web]

2007-2011: Jammel's high school, Tunisia [High school diploma]